Vijay Rajendra Bakare

Mobile: +918446550810 / +918888673648

Email: v89vijay@gmail.com

Career Summary

3+ years of techno functional experience in Finance Domain(Core Banking, Investment Banking) for **6** months and Ecommerce Domain **2.8** year.

Experience in executing project in agile framework, and creating project plan estimate with minimal efforts. Hands on experience in JAVA/J2EE and technologies such as Spring boot REST, Micro services with Spring and JPA

Hibernate and Secondary hibernate cache (GUAVA CACHE).

Experience in white box testing with JUnit 3.0, UI testing and Mockito. Use Github and SVN for Source Tree.

Experience in designing and development rich internet applications technologies and frameworks like HTML, XML Java Script, JQuery, CSS and AJAX implementation.

Excellent grasp over the technology which adds to manage the project smoothly.

Involved in preparing the Proof of concept (POC).

Preparing Weekly Status report and Daily Task monitoring using JIRA and Confluence Time sheet.

Right kind of attitude to perform in the organization and to be committed and self-motivated with strong and sound programming knowledge.

Technical and functional skills

Programming Languages: JAVA/J2EE, JDBC, XML, SQL.

Web Technologies: Microservices, Spring Rest web services, JSP/Servlet, HTML, Java Script JQuery and AJAX.

Web and Application Servers: Tomcat, JBOSS...

Databases: Oracle, MS SQL. **Methodologies:** Agile, Waterfall.

Functional Domain: Core Banking, Ecommerce Portal.

Documentation: Spring Swagger.

Experience Summary

Sysnik It Solutions Pvt. Ltd. Pune Duration: Dec 2018 - till date

Designation: Sr. Java Developer

Starsun Technology Pvt. Ltd. Pune Duration: March 2016 - Dec 2018

Designation: Jr. Java Developer

Education Summary

Specialization	University/College	Year
B.E. Computer	University of Pune	2014
Diploma Computer	Maharashtra Technical Board Mumbai	2010
HSC	Maharashtra Technical Board Mumbai	2007
SSC	Maharashtra Technical Board Mumbai	2004

Certifications

Successfully completed It Professional Diploma from Itpreneur Data System Pvt. Ltd., Pune.

Professional Experience

Project: 1

Title: Core Banking System **Duration:** December 2018 to till date.

Technologies used: Java8, Spring boot micro services framework, JPA Hibernate with MS SQL, JWT Spring Security, SVN Repo, Swagger, Spring Tool Suite, Maven, Apache Tomcat and Windows10.

Organization: Sysnik It Solutions **Role:** Senior Java Developer

Description: Sysnik is product based company. The company already have tab banking products in the market.

Sysnik is developing a Core Banking System which will cater to day to day retail banking needs.

Responsibilities:

- Understand requirement analyzing estimating and develop product using Spring Boot
- Responsible to prepare the Low Level design document and creating the reusable components for across the application
- Responsibility to do the Code Review and preparing the QA for other application components.
- Worked on Spring and Hibernate mapping using annotation.
- Prepare detailed design documents of each screen.
- Implementing and enhancing new feature to our applications.
- Addressing day to day technical issues, and complete build test in deploy phase
- Used Log4J for logging and debugging and JUnit for testing
- Monitoring the development process solving the issue and concerns regarding the project.

Project: 2

Title: Data Accessibility in school using Smart card Duration: May 2018 To December 2018.

Technologies used: Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Hibernate, Spring, JQuery, JavaScript, And MySql., Apache Tomcat and

Windows10.

Organization: Starsun Technology. Client: Podar International School

Role: Junior Java Developer

Description: This project is developed to maintain the database of the students, staff, admin and the parents. The student's information like personal information, educational details from the admission in the school till his completion of studies is updated. Also it is stored in the database permanently. Same way the staff information is stored. The parents can view the details of the student online. The student, staff, admin can enter the School premises using the Smart card. All the rights to view and edit is given to Admin

Responsibilities:

- Understand requirement analyzing estimating and develop product using Spring Boot
- Responsible to prepare the Low Level design document and creating the reusable components for across the application
- Responsible for development of an application from scratch.
- Responsible for Admin Interface Using JSP apply validation and other effects by using JQuery.
- Responsible for Coding POJO Classes & Implementing JavaScript validation.
- Writing Hibernate Mapping Files.
- Responsible To Make Spring Controller, Service And Dao Layers
- Make unit testing on Project.

Project: 3

Title: Angel Music Duration: February 2017 To May 2018.

Technologies used: Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Hibernate, Spring, JQuery, JavaScript, And MySql., Apache Tomcat and Windows10.

Organization: Starsun Technology. Client: Angel Music Group

Role: Junior Java Developer

Description:

It is Web Application of Angel Music Company. Angel Music Company having Five Branches in Pune City. So in that Web Application one is Super Admin for Five Branches. Also Individual Branch Admin & Branch Reception for that Branch. Branch Reception work is filling Enquiry form of Student & Follow up that Student on Daily Basic. Also

Branch Reception taking Request for instrument Rent & Repair. Branch Admin having authority of taking payment Regarding request in admission, Rent & Repair. Super Admin having authority of accessing all Data of Branch like Admission, Rent & Repair etc

Responsibilities:

- Understand requirement analyzing estimating and develop product using Spring Boot
- Responsible to prepare the Low Level design document and creating the reusable components for across the application
- Understanding business requirement functional specification of client module.
- Prepare detailed design documents of each screen.
- Responsible for Coding POJO Classes & Implementing JavaScript validation.
- Developed GUI using JQuery JSON and Java Script
- Responsible To Make Spring Controller, Service And Dao Layers
- Design JSON Request according to front end pages through AZAX and JQuery.
- Make unit testing on Project.

Project: 4

Title: Policy Soft **Duration:** December 2018 to till date.

Technologies used: Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Hibernate, Spring, JQuery, JavaScript, And MySql., Apache Tomcat and

Windows10.

Organization: Starsun Technology. Client: Allianz Group

Role: Junior Java Developer

Description: This project provides all screens to customer to log in and view all their account information, make fund transfers, apply for a loan. etc.

Responsibilities:

- Developing JSP pages and the view and controller related fields using Spring MVC framework
- Using java script for validation
- Troubleshoot the problem and fixes the bugs of java related program.
- Design JSON according to Front end by AZAX and JQuery
- Mapping of Hibernate association such as one-to-many, many-to-one.
- Process JSON response according to the request, send it back to front end after the logic processing.
- Using Java Script / JQuery validation
- Written SQL, HQL, named queries and Criteria queries.
- Integrating view module with MySql using Hibernate.
- Make unit testing of project
- Building and developing the application on testing and production servers.

Project: 5

Title: Shital Packaging Jar **Duration:** May 2016 To Sep 2016.

Technologies used: Core Java, Servlets, JSP, Hibernate, Spring, JQuery, JavaScript, And MySql., Apache Tomcat and

Windows10.

Organization: Starsun Technology. Client: Shital Packaging

Description: It is Web Application of Shital Packaging Industry. Shital Packaging Industry having two Parts. One is Cello tape Manufacturing and one is Jar delivery in their area. In cello tape industry they want record of purchase, selling etc. Also Invoice with GST added. In jar type they want daily customer records with Numbers of jar.

Responsibilities:

- Functioned as **Developer**
- Responsible For Admin Interface Using JSP apply validation and other effects by using JQuery.
- Responsible For Coding POJO Classes & Implementing Business Logic.
- Implementing Payment Gateway of PayUMoney.
- Responsible To Make Spring Controller, Service And Dao Layers

Make unit testing on Project

Personal information

Name: Vijay Bakare
Date of Birth: 01-05 -1989
Passport: **Z4003465**

Passport: **Z4003465** Expiry: 21-08-2016

Languages Known: English, Hindi, and Marathi

Marital Status: Unmarried

Permanent Address: Sandeep Khandve Apartment, Near Hotel Durga, Wadgaon Shinde Road, Lohagaon Pune

411047

Declaration

I hereby declare that the information given above are true and correct to the best of my knowledge and understanding.

Place: Pune Vijay Bakare